SOME SCENES IN THE STORY TAKE PLACE IN
VARIOUS PARTS OF INDIA INCLUDING DELHI
BUT FOR THE CONVENIENCE OF THE VIEWERS,
THE CHARACTERS COMMUNICATE IN TAMIL
[aircraft whirring]
Chennai Tower, this is Deccan Air 582.
Minimum fuel.
Requesting landing clearance.
Go around, Deccan Air 582.
Unable to go around.
I said we have
a fuel emergency. Goddammit!
I say again, Deccan Air 582...
I'm running out of fuel.
Let me land!
There's something's wrong.
They are ignoring protocol.
Chennai Tower,
requesting reason for denial!
You're not cleared to land!
-Why aren't you letting them land?
-Who are you? Guards!
Maara?
Maara, what's going on there?
-Why won't they let us land?
-Do you copy?
Tambaram Air Force. Runway 1-5.
Land there!
Do you have enough fuel for that?
We've enough for one landing!
-You sure you want us to proceed?
-I'm sure!
-We'll be in trouble.
-Land at Tambaram, damn it!
-I'll handle it!
-Roger.
[clamoring]
Che! Che...
[alarm beeping]
Parade! Attention!
Faster. Careful.
Come in, Tambaram Ground Control,
Captain Chaitanya Rao here, batch of 1987.
-Please acknowledge.
-You can't land here, Captain.
This is military territory.
Turn around now! This is an order!
[alarm beeping]
Go fast! Go!
[gunshot]
-Security breach at gate one!
-Stop!
Shit! Shit! Shit!
[screaming]
[tires screeching]
Sorry, Maara!
[indistinct yelling]
[siren wailing]
Che, are you okay!
Can you hear me?
SURIYA
Che?
PARESH RAWAL
Che!
APARNA BALAMURALI
URVASHI
KARUNAS
CO-STARRING
'PADMA SHRI' DR.MOHAN BABU.M
[inaudible]
[indistinct chattering]
SOORARAI POTTRU
[PRAISE THE BRAVE]
[train horn blaring]
Aren't you ashamed of eating meat
soon after the pilgrimage?
He's no longer in the army.
His relatives say he's unemployed now.
Why are you hell-bent on meeting him?
-What's the big deal?
-It's unprecedented.
It's unheard of for a girl's family
to visit a boy.
He refused to see you!
Why are you dying to see him?
Good question.
He refused to treat me
like an animal for sale,
that's why we're going.
She'll choose her husband
like Sita chose Lord Rama.
-Right, kiddo?
-Stop calling her kiddo.
You're spoiling this buffalo.
Stop taking her side.
Are you talking about me?
Am I really spoilt?
I'm the only one in the family
to clear 12th grade in one go
but you paid lakhs
-to make him an engineer.
-Don't drag me into this.
-You're the spoilt brat, not me.
-Ask her to shut up, Dad.
Listen, girl,
only sons provide for parents.
Daughters move in with their
husbands after marriage and enjoy life.
Move it! You and your pearls of wisdom!
Move aside!
Oh, God!
This is what happens if you open
your mouth unnecessarily.
-Get your hands off me!
-I shouldn't have helped him!
Isn't this a reserved compartment?
What's that stench? Dried fish? Yuck!
Horrid fellow!
Are we that repulsive to you?
We get off at Sholavandhan.
Then these seats will be all yours.
This is an express train.
Won't stop at Sholavandhan.
It will! For the last six months,
my dear Maara
didn't let any train pass
without stopping at Sholavandhan.
They had no choice but to stop here!
So, every time I go to Madurai
I'll have to endure this stench.
Mister, you can keep these
seats for yourself!
We won't be commuting
in trains anymore.
Really? Why so?
We'll be flying!
-He's bringing airplane to us!
-Yeah!
-Who?
-Our Maara!
On this round ball of dirt
On this round ball of dirt,
Behold man's mad dance!
When his eyelids last shut,
He is but a procession on hearse.
Fill up the cauldron with bubbling booze!
Stomp and shake
At our dear man's final walk!
Rich or poor,
All are dealt the same notch!
On their final passage,
All get blown the conch!
Rich or poor,
All are dealt the same notch!
On their final passage,
All get blown the conch!
All that he can take when dead
Is the rupee-coin on his forehead!
That one rupee coin!
That and that alone!
All that he can take when dead
Is the rupee-coin on his forehead!
Let us beat and dance
To make even the dead prance!
Women will wail only till the streets end!
As the pyre burns, the rib cage yearns!
Legions of near and dear,
Yet no one to tag along with him!
Acres of lands were his,
Yet six feet of soil is what is!
Legions of near and dear,
Yet no one to tag along with him!
Acres of lands were his,
Yet six feet of soil is what is!
The one dancing
in black shirt is the groom.
Is he the groom?
-Look how the groom is dancing!
-Maara!
-The bride's family is here.
-What is he saying?
Our community will humiliate us,
if they see this!
They're watching you, man!
Who cares?
That man danced for every death here.
The whole village
should be dancing for him!
-Come and dance!
-That's right!
-God forbid she starts dancing!
-Stop.
Hey, come.
Rocks! Palm trees!
-Barren lands!
-Everything is for your daughter!
Yeah, right! The groom doesn't seem
interested in the marriage.
Oh, no! He's keen too!
Your girl is lucky! Please come.
Please have some fryums.
We didn't come
all the way to eat fryums.
Don't you have cakes?
There's not even a toilet here
and you want cakes!
Don't shush me.
It's the truth
Hey! Since we're talking truths,
I'm completely broke.
I've a huge loan
and all I earn goes for repayment.
The government took our fertile lands
for a dam and gave us these barren lands.
Isn't that, right?
All I have is
an idea to start an airline.
But that too
has been rejected by 24 banks.
Look, mister.
Men are in a queue to marry
my beautiful and talented daughter.
I've been rejected by 20 grooms so far.
-Silly girl. Shut up!
-Why are you shushing?
I don't sew, cook, dance or sing!
Mr. Military! She's just pulling your leg.
-She knows all that and more. Right?
-Yes,
but I won't do any of it.
All I want to do is start a bakery.
All this brutal honesty can be tiring.
-Let's eat.
-Let's go!
-Come, let's go...
-Wait.
It's not our tradition to eat unless
the discussion is fruitful.
And we don't let our guests go hungry.
-Let's eat.
-Hey!
So your friend's bringing planes here?
Yeah, bro!
Have you been in an airplane?
"Been in one"? I've flown one!
When my pilot friend drives
he hands me the steering
when he smokes.
What? It's true, bro!
Give them water to drink.
How will you finance your airline?
Hey, that's grown-up talk.
Why are you asking about it?
That's exactly why I'm asking.
Quite the shrewd kid!
So, 20 boys rejected you?
Twenty-four banks rejected you.
Let's talk about that first.
-They weren't that bright.
-Those men weren't either.
Be quiet and eat!
One, two, three...
Just three steps to start an airline!
Seems simple.
Starting a bakery must be even simpler.
Why haven't you done that yet?
I'm still on step one.
Looking for finance.
I'm waiting to get the money.
I know what a bank is.
What is Ven-tu-re Capitalists?
Venture Capitalists.
Banks give loans against collateral.
But for Venture Capitalist, VC
your idea is your collateral.
You get funds if they like your idea.
Then you should catch a VC.
Who is that? VC?
Paresh Goswami.
The owner of Jaz Airlines.
He realized his dream
with little to no help. My hero.
With so many basic needs unfulfilled
in our country
who needs planes?
A century ago,
they said we don't need electricity.
Fifty years ago,
they said we don't need cars.
Who decides that?
The rich decide for the rest.
-Keep quiet. You won't understand.
-Smart girl.
Okay.
Okay with what?
I'm okay marrying you.
That was quick.
Are you insane?
Sometimes, no matter how hard we think,
we end up doing what we want.
-Why waste time?
-That's Maara!
But I give enough thought
before making up my mind.
There she goes.
I'll tell you tomorrow.
That's my girl. Eat, dear.
He fussed about eating here,
now he missed the train
and has to stay the night!
Destiny!
That way.
Hey!
You have a big house in the village.
Why do you stay here without electricity?
Getting electricity is no big deal.
Even teacher Rajangam's house
didn't have electricity 20 years ago.
I don't go there anymore.
Air... Air India!
Where are you going?
I'm going in Air India, Dad!
You want planes when there are no roads?
First, learn to cut hair!
Is it a law that a son must follow
his father's trade?
No matter what they study,
it's their fate
to get into the family business.
Keep the pot on your head, kid,
I'll do the rest in the morning.
Dad, it would look awkward!
What if I cut off your ear in the dark?
First bring trains to our village!
It's really hard for us
to commute, you know.
My father, the six-fingered
school teacher,
wrote numerous letters to the government
to make the train stop here.
How long will you keep writing?
As long as I can hold a pen.
Politicians go around happily
in trains and planes!
Why would they care about us?
The teacher kept writing petitions,
but nothing changed.
I picked up a stone.
-Hear us, Central Government!
-[all] Hear us, Central Government!
-Stop the express train here!
-[all] Stop the express train here!
-Deceive us, no more!
-[train horn blaring]
[all] Deceive us, no more!
[all clamoring]
Down with police brutality!
Deceive us, no more!
We want the train!
[people clamoring]
Maara!
Kaali!
-Kaali...
-Maara!
Maara!
Lift him up!
-I can't open my eye, Maara!
-Lift him up!
What happened?
Oh, my God! You're bleeding!
Your son pelted stones
to stop the train at Sholavandhan.
Esakki's son got hurt,
he could've lost an eye!
My God! He got hurt in the eye!
Come in!
Esakki kept quiet because it was my son.
But, God, the way he looked at me...
It killed me.
I preach non-violence to everyone,
but my own son doesn't listen to me.
Dad! You've always said time is precious.
And that the train stopping here
will change our lives!
This is how things change!
There's no need to do good
by destroying yourself.
Aren't you educated?
You're a teacher's son, not a rogue.
If you want to stop the train,
you write to the division head.
Did you do that?
-You wrote petitions. Did anything happen?
-Maara...
We got electricity because of that.
Get inside, Maara!
Not that petition, Mom!
I know which petition he's talking about.
Let him talk.
Listen, he hasn't eaten yet!
You know he blabbers when he's hungry!
-Come in...
-If he has the guts, let him say it!
First thing tomorrow,
I'll have him arrested.
Don't say that. He's our son!
What did you do
when mom had pregnancy complications?
You just sent petitions
asking for a medical camp!
You'll have me arrested?
You should be arrested
for killing my sister.
-Maara! No...
-Quiet, Mom!
We had to take Kaali
to the hospital outside the town!
This armchair idealist
will bury us all with his petitions!
You're a bloody failure!
And will always be one!
Please, no!
Maara, please come in...
If violence is wrong,
why the fuck did you just hit me?
Thanks for the respect, son.
Don't even light my pyre
when I die. Leave!
What have you done?
What have you done? Maara!
Maara... Stop!
He's leaving! Maara!
Maara! Where are you going? Wait!
And then?
Then I joined the National Defense Academy
and then the Air Force.
Quite the angry man!
Were you as bad in the Air Force?
[planes whooshing]
He says the snacks don’t reach him.
-All the postal guys...
-Ma!
[softly] Show it to him.
The postal guys eat them up.
-Maara has sent a letter.
-I'm sending two boxes this time
with a note saying,
"You can take one box,
but give the other to my son."
Hey! Who told you to go there?
Get it here!
Should I read it to you?
I am a third grader,
and a teacher's wife!
I can read myself.
Look at him writing chits.
Writing letters for his son
and then hiding them!
I will shred them all one day!
Dear, Mom...
[softly] Look! He's listening.
And dear, Kaali,
how are you?
I'm good here."
This shows how much he loves us.
I passed my ex-cams, Mom.
-It's "exam," ma!
-That's what I said. Shut up!
Che secured first spot.
And I was second. Seby stood fourth.
I am Pilot officer
Nedumaaran Rajangam now."
There is an officer called Naidu,
who torments me with his rules
and tortures me with dos and don'ts
just like our teacher!"
Bring this stupid Naidu to me.
I'm going to break his neck
like I do with chickens.
Move round and round
Like a surging hurricane!
Lunge far and wide
Like a bull off its leash!
Keep the act alive! Rock the damn house!
Like the blazing sun,
Set your path on fire!
Sir!
Come on, trainees! Double up!
Move fast, I say!
-Maara? How are you?
-I'm fine, Kaali! How are you?
-Where is mom?
-She's fine!
Get her quick! I only have three minutes!
She's bringing your father!
She'll be here any second!
Hang on! Maara...
She's here!
Hurry up!
-Come soon!
-Ask them to hurry!
He can't walk fast, you know.
-Here.
-Yeah.
Hello, Maara?
-Mom?
-Maara? Your dad has come.
-Mom...-Shall I put him on?
-Mom, I can hear you.
-Maara?
I can't hear anything.
I can hear you! Please talk!
Maara! Hello?
I can hear you! Tell mom to speak.
Give it to dad!
-The line got disconnected!
-Oh, no!
I can hear you, Kaali.
Put dad on the line!
Why will he talk to a loser?
He won't talk to me.
-What?
-He won't talk to me.
-Hold him!
-I hear you, Dad! Mom!
-I'll just make one more call!
-Hold him carefully!
Appa...
-Nedumaaran.
-Sir!
People are waiting.
Everyone gets only three minutes.
Call next month! Move.
Move!
Logistically, we can save a lot, sir.
How will one Mi-26 alone suffice?
This being a joint operation
with the army,
we can transport airmen
in their armored troop carriers.
One chopper will do.
We can ration fuel
and cut down extra costs...
You will cut down nothing, Nedumaaran.
Don't be stingy.
Intelligence says
insurgent activity has risen
in the Narsapuram forests.
We eliminate risk by increasing
our ground numbers.
I'm not being stingy,
I'm being smart, sir.
-So... Chaitanya!
-Sir!
-Is he saying I am not smart?
-No, sir!
Fifty rounds around the parade ground!
Fifty kilos dead weight!
Take your pals with you!
Hundred rounds, 80 kilos,
in one and half hours!
Move!
Where the hell did she go?
We missed our last train
because of her...
-Hey!
-Sundari!
What are you doing with him
so late at night?
He lost his heart to this cunning belle!
Into the curve of her bangle,
Trapped, he fell!
She pulled off one hell of a heist
And took off into the night!
Many, many clouds jumped from the skies
To catch her stride with their eyes!
You brigand!
Oh, you brigand!
Left behind an everlasting mark!
She's gonna be trouble!
-Hey, Kaali!
-Yes, buddy?
I'll kill you!
Why is she ranting?
You two were just talking, right?
Why? Should I tell you everything?
After so many rejections,
I was scared my niece
will remain a spinster.
This is auspicious month.
Got to book a marriage hall soon!
Marriage hall?
The groom looks dashing!
No!
What the hell?
Are you saying no to the marriage hall?
I am saying no to the marriage.
The boy himself has agreed!
Why are you rejecting?
Did you ask the 20 men
why they rejected me?
-That's different!
-Shut up.
-Keep quiet.
-She said no.
May I ask why?
Yes! Yes, you may!
You're already married
to your planes!
I'm married, too.
Let's make something out of that first.
Serves you right for your arrogance.
A devil just like you!
No loss, buddy!
She already looks like a bun,
we can find someone better than her.
You calm down!
I'm sure she has her reasons.
Is this needed?
Hey, broker. I'll deal with you later.
Broker! Is this what you do all the time?
You brought us all the way here to say no?
What is your problem?
That I rejected him
Or that you couldn't reject your husband?
-Drop them.
-I don't want to drive them!
Let them walk!
It's a waste of fuel.
Hey, get into the vehicle.
This pristine belle leaves this soil
With my heart in tow!
With her snarky words,
This enchantress traps me now!
One gaze of hers and I fall apart!
In the blink of an eye,
She left me a blubbering mess!
Why laugh after tearing me
To shreds, you fiend?
You've knotted me up
In the curve of your hip!
Your two eyes
BOMMI BAKERY
Pin me down!
Why laugh after tearing me
To shreds, you fiend?
You've knotted me up
In the curve of your hip...
-We cannot give loans for airplanes.
-The idea...
You know we are a tiny rural bank.
Morning, ma'am.
May I meet Mr. Mittal.
-I am Nedumaaran...
-I have many of these already, sir.
With your husky voice, you stole my heart!
You set ablaze this beetle
Burrowing an electric pole!
You threw my heart into complete disarray!
You flashed a smile into the darkness
To give birth to the dawn!
She came by like fire!
My head splits
Into a million sweet smithereens!
Will this refreshing drink
Be my forever fate?
Why laugh after tearing me
To shreds, you fiend?
You've knotted me up
In the curve of your hip!
I can't meet anyone right now. I'm late.
Sir...
Ma'am, one meeting with Mr. Paresh.
You always make these fritters,
why can't you make cakes?
Look at the mugs wanting cakes!
Bommi Cakes!
Sweet news for the sweet-toothed!
Mr. Paresh Goswami...
Look! I already have 100 of your cards!
You can't meet him.
Why don't you understand?
You sound more like a fortune teller
than a programmer!
The logic is wrong. Override this.
-Yeah, try that.
-It's running, sir!
Source code ready! Brilliant, sir!
It's working, sir! Brilliant, sir!
Yes, he is.
How many millions
did you make from this?
Corrupting IIT kids with his lofty ideas!
You should've become
a professor at IIT, sir.
-Yes, sir! You should!
-Yes, sir!
If I was really that smart,
I would've moved out of here.
The two of you quit the Air Force
yapping about some big dreams.
But you accomplished nothing.
Son-in-law! Sebastian!
You need an ex-servicemen loan, right?
No one respects him out there.
Especially, now with Naidu
sitting in Tambaram.
-He won't sign.
-I can't hear you!
How can you, if you’re stuffed
to your gills with my food?
Of course, you won't.
Thank you, sir.
This loan won't be approved
without Naidu's nod.
Be quiet when we get there, alright?
Che's gone through a lot
to get us this appointment.
-So, you shut up! Understand?
-Mmm.
Do you get it or not?
-I got it!
-Good boy! Go!
Nedumaaran,
let me spell it out for you.
Even though I can,
I won't sign these referral papers.
You want my best pilot Chaitanya resign
and ruin his life.
I don't like people who break rules.
You are not fit to be a leader!
Let's go!
Sir.
Seby? Maara? Boys, what happened?
The same crap after all these years.
-Egoistic jackasses, both!
-Maara, stop!
Forget him and the banks!
Let's figure out our next move!
I just did!
-Hold on, Maara!
-Maara!
-Twenty-thousand rupees, yes?
-Yes.
-Have a nice journey.
-Thank you.
-Ma'am, please check those in.
-Please consider my request.
I've just two boxes of fryums and pickles.
-They'll be ruined if I check them in!
-Ma'am, that's not my problem.
-You're delaying the passengers.
-My sister's pregnant...
Sir, please come forward.
Do you know anything about
pregnancy cravings?
Of course not, 'cause you're a man!
-Have you ever been pregnant?
-Send the manager to counter 4.
Yeah, call the manager!
-If that's a lady, she'll understand.
-Excuse me, ma'am.
I'll take it. No problem.
-I got this.
-Thank you very much, sir.
He is with me. Check me in now!
-Check me in! Yeah!
-Sure, ma'am.
You won't run away with these, right?
Fryums and pickles.
Are you a reporter?
How did you guess?
You ask too many questions.
This flight is full of media people.
Paresh Goswami himself is flying us
to the RRTV Awards.
-Is that where you are going?
-Yes.
-But I've not seen you in media before.
-Your boarding pass, ma'am?
I'm Chitra Ramaswamy.
Senior Producer, All India Radio.
Why are you going?
Sir.
Am I bothering you
with my questions?
I still want an answer.
Why are you going?
-To meet someone.
-Who?
-[toilet flushing]
-[humming]
[exhales deeply]
Good afternoon, sir.
-Excuse me.
-Sir.
My brother Bhawarlal's outside.
-Please send him in.
-Sure, sir! Sure, sir! Sure, sir!
-[breathing deeply]
-[door opens]
Shall I cancel the flight?
Not necessary.
It's just an anxiety attack. It's okay.
Change your shirt.
Take your pill.
Bhawar...
Do the staff use the same restrooms
as the guests?
A steward just used one.
I'll have it cleaned.
Shivdas Airport Services.
Okay, I'll have him fired.
Paresh Goswami?
Why do you want meet such a big shot?
To discuss a business partnership.
-He won't let you get anywhere near him.
-But I'll make him my business partner.
Are you kidding?
He won't even talk to you. Want to bet?
-What if he did?
-Out of the question.
We can just applaud
at his speech.
[indistinct announcement over PA]
Why are you getting up?
That call's for business class.
You didn't say what you'll do if you lose.
I'll tell you what to do when I win.
You're in business class?
You must be really rich.
Then why wait in the queue?
You're really strange!
You spent 40,000
for business class?
Didn't you tell me I can't
meet him at function?
So, business class.
You don't need 40,000,
20,000's enough.
I'll be returning by train, third class.
I'm not rich, ma'am.
Emptied my bank account to buy it.
Anyways, please take care
of my fryums and pickles.
-Please take care.
-Sure.
-Good evening, sir. Welcome onboard.
-Ladies and gentlemen,
this is your Captain Sharma
from flight deck...
-Hey guys, that's Paresh.
-Hello.
...we welcome you all
onboard Jaz Airlines,
JZ 433, Chennai to Mumbai.
We have with us today,
our chairman, Mr. Goswami...
Hello, Mr. Paresh.
...our heartiest welcome to you, sir.
We'll be flying
32,000 feet above sea level...
I'll see you in Bombay.
Congratulations on the award, sir.
Proud moment for the Jaz family.
-Hello, sir. I'm Nedumaaran.
-Excuse me!
You're the inspiration for my airline.
May I request you to return to your seat?
-Right, sir.
-It's fine.
It's a pleasure, sir.
You intend to start an airline?
Sir... Yes, sir.
An airline for the common man.
A low-cost airline for everyone.
-Nedurangan?
-It's Nedumaaran.
Yes.
Would these people you speak of
want three square meals a day
or to fly in a plane?
They don't need to choose.
With my ticket fare, they can do both.
-Sir...
-Are you planning
to do some kind of social service?
I want to execute this idea with you, sir.
Everyone in here has an idea
to become a billionaire.
They all sound great.
But practically impossible.
I never waste time
talking about the impossible.
My ideas are practically possible.
So, you want to sell tickets at low price
and still be profitable?
You think this didn't occur to us
all these years?
Yes, sir.
Today, no Indian can book air tickets
without a travel agency.
We all know that.
A big chunk of the fare
goes to the travel agent as commission.
Like the middlemen in farming.
What if we bypass that?
Bypass a travel agency?
Then how will customers book tickets?
The internet!
They book tickets through computers.
Wow!
So you're gonna make a farmer,
who has never owned a computer
nor know internet,
book tickets and fly.
Fantastic!
Internet is available in 500 post offices
in Tamil Nadu alone.
And there is internet
in 1,453 Reliance petrol bunks
all over India.
They can book the ticket there!
Then the farmers
won't need computers nor internet, right?
But this requires
a specialized booking software.
I don't think you're aware of it.
You must be aware of Interworld.
They make ticketing software
for all major airlines.
They've agreed to do it.
You can make a tailor fly
alongside a textile baron.
-Yes, I can make that happen.
-Sir.
But I won't.
Sir... Why not?
Would anyone want to see beggars
and coolies on planes?
I don't want my passengers to suffer.
So that's why your air fare
is so expensive?
I have an airline to run, my friend.
-But what you're doing is...
-Get him out!
Put him in economy.
Hello, sir?
Do you mind coming with me, sir?
Why the fuck should I go?
-I paid for the ticket!
-Please cooperate...
Lay a hand on me,
I'll rip your throat out.
[whispering]
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is Captain Sharma again,
from the flight deck.
Due to technical difficulties,
this plane will return to Chennai.
We apologize for the inconvenience.
You own the ticket.
I own the plane, my friend.
This way, sir.
I know the drill. My job here is done.
Madam...
your fryums and pickles.
-Thank you.
-See you.
-Nedumaaran...
-Yeah.
-Take care.
-Thanks.
Bye.
Mr. Nedumaaran.
I was on that flight, too.
I heard what you told Paresh.
I'm Prakash Babu. SCI Venture Capitalists.
I know. I've been
to your office many times.
Alright.
I'll give you the time
I didn't back then. Okay?
Five minutes. Come along.
-[horn honking]
-[siren wailing]
Take care of table two.
-Sir, coffee.
-Maaran...
If you're hungry, we could've gone
to the five-star hotel nearby.
This is the best place
to explain my idea.
-Are you well, bro?
-Yes, brother.
-What will you have?
-I ordered a dosa.
What's the connection between
an Udupi hotel and airlines?
Today, an air ticket to Delhi
costs 12,000 rupees.
First class costs 20,000.
Definitely.
You need to spend a lot
to run an airline.
-Sir, dosa.
-Flight maintenance, hangar charges,
pilot salary, fuel costs, etc...
It's a costly business!
Dig in.
Please have it.
Table number five hasn't received
their poori yet. Please check.
[indistinct chattering]
Table number five, 60 rupees.
How is it, sir?
Actually, it's good.
-Very good.
-Thank you, sir!
It's very good.
Brother!
-Where do you get your provisions?
-Chintamani stores at Moore market!
Who is their biggest customer?
The five-star hotel next street.
You know what's funny?
Their chefs have our food for dinner.
Please eat.
Bro?
Have you had dosa
at the five-star hotel nearby?
When I get dosa here
for less than 20 bucks,
why will I waste 200 bucks there?
Sure, brother.
-The dosa is great here. Enjoy!
-Yeah.
See?
Everyone's happy.
The same dish is sold under a fancy name
at the five-star hotel.
The only difference is,
it's cheap out here.
But no difference in taste and hygiene.
No needless expenses.
My airline will operate the same way.
Why provide food and newspapers
for an hour-long flight?
I will neither provide these to them
nor charge for them.
10% of costs drop right away.
We keep our flights light.
No extra food or staff.
Other airlines do two trips a day.
We will do six.
Six trips?
How?
There is Flight Duty Time Limitation.
Staff cannot fly
for more than eight hours.
We can have three shifts.
Three shifts. 18 hours of flying time.
Deduct C&D checks,
cleaning and fueling,
we can still fly for 14 hours.
Only humans tire. Planes don't, right?
But this isn't the norm.
It's not the convention.
Let's break every damn rule.
Look, sir.
No tables are empty,
none of the waiters are idle.
In simple words, our airline
is the Udupi Hotel in the sky.
You didn't tell me
you were starting an Udupi Hotel.
-Not on this street.
-Then, it's fine!
-If I...
-...don't get on board
I've tried 23 VCs and 56 banks so far.
And all they said is,
"Who is this crazy?"
If you say the same,
I'll just go find VC number 25.
-Excuse me.
-Sure.
Sir, bill.
-Maaran.
-Sir.
Come to my office next month. April 8th.
Convince the rest of the board too.
Okay? Bye.
Yeah.
Apparently there's a girl named Annamayil.
My mom's blackmailing
to not talk unless I meet her.
I'm going to Madurai
to straighten things out.
The kids have gone nuts
after you showed them that film on planes.
We were doomed to carts, Esakki.
At least let the kids fly!
Maara!
THE CORPORATION OF MADURAI,
WELCOMES YOU
I told my brother not to borrow
from that loan shark Arivu!
He seized our land.
We now have drunks near home!
Hey! Get up!
Isn't this that girl's shop?
Your mom told us to meet Annamayil.
Let's go!
-Let's buy sweets!
-Hello, son-in-law!
What brings you here?
Have a drink!
You rejected us
and now call him son-in-law?
Load up two kilos of cakes!
Is this a scrap shop? It's a bakery!
It's "pack two kilos of cakes."
Whatever!
Give me samples of those two.
Eating for free is called sample, eh?
Nasty habit!
How dare you come here
after calling me a bun?
Let's go, buddy.
This bakery sucks.
Are you married?
Yes. Two kids. You?
We're meeting a prospective bride.
That's why we came to buy sweets.
So you've been at it for three years?
What about the airplane company?
You know SCI? The Venture Capitalist?
They've accepted my project.
Few formalities left with DGCA licenses,
and the NOC.
So you're still on step one?
I'm already on step three!
Hello!
I said I'll launch in a month!
-Oh.
-Ah, now you're gobsmacked?
You wish!
Had you bought an auto or bus,
you would've made some money!
Is your husband doing
anything great?
We're set to open
another shop, mind you!?
What does the little one want?
-Want some cake?
-I packed these myself!
Price is Rs.150, but for you it's Rs.100.
Why is he so pissed?
Shall we go?
You call this cake?
It tastes like feet.
Sugary crap! Spit it out!
It's pretty good, buddy!
-This is crap!
-Damn country bumpkins!
Would any sane person open a bakery
near a liquor shop?
It should've been near
a school or college, right?
You need brains to work that out!
Buddy! Maara!
She's still a spinster!
Nothing has happened yet.
What has not happened?
That bun-girl isn't married yet!
Her loudmouth uncle told me!
Can I eat her cakes now?
Sweet news for the sweet-toothed!
Milk cakes! Cheese cakes! Butter cakes!
-Buy one, get one free!
-Hi.
Bommi Cakes!
It just melts in your mouth!
Those were your friend's kids, right?
-Cheese cakes...
-Why did you bluff?
Come on. Tell me!
-Hey, bun-face!
-Bommi...
The world calls us crackpots.
No one wants to marry either of us.
So why don't we get married?
How about that?
So why didn't you see this crackpot
in three years?
Back then, I couldn't even feed myself.
Those barren lands are green now!
Good income!
My business kicks off in a month!
Good enough, right?
-Stuff just melts in your mouth!
-Hey.
Bommi Bakery!
And if that fails too?
Who says it's only a husband
who provides for the wife?
Won't you feed me?
They are romancing! Romance!
What do you say, bun-face?
-But I have three conditions.
-What are those?
Kiddo! We just got things up and running.
Why screw it up?
Number one, it's our money,
not yours or mine.
-Understood?
-Yeah.
Two, my business is not inferior
to your business in anyway.
-Understood?
-Yeah.
2.1: because I know your brain
can't process more than two.
-Hey!
-Our family is very important to me.
And if you let us down,
I'll poison your food!
If you're cool with all this,
we can marry tomorrow.
I already said yes to all of it!
You better think hard
because I won't divorce you.
I won't ask for it either!
So how come you agreed?
Sometimes, no matter
how hard you think
you end up doing what you want.
Why waste time?
Listen to me.
Buy one loony and get another one.
Buy two loonies and get both free!
Both loonies are available! Come get them!
A thief from Sholavandhan
has robbed the bakery!
Hey, rugged one!
Cuddle me just this once!
A wild rabbit, I am!
You are the one to snare me!
A thorny jungle, I am!
With your slick sickle
And your sly looks, you entice me!
Hey stealthy cat! Like a ball of yarn,
You spin me around!
Like the coins in the folds of my saree,
You caress me!
As strong as a boulder, I am!
With a magic wand in your hand,
As a delicate thread, you weave me!
An elephant's hunger, I am, to you!
A corn kernel, you are, to me!
To all of you who came to this wedding
jam cakes will be provided!
Savor and rejoice!
Ward off the evil eye!
Just thirty bucks?
-You deserve less.
-Oh, really?
With love, you make me tremble!
When I am on fire,
You stand there, humble!
You make me shiver with your gaze,
And you make my heart graze!
I can't be an adolescent forever,
To blush, I don't even remember!
Where did you find this power? Seize me!
You tease me with a starter,
You make my mouth water
To my joy, why don't you cater?
Embrace me!
Shall I punish you?
Or relish you?
Little by little, I am gonna
Tease and finish you!
Bommi, for your new bakery, my dear.
-Bommi?
-Yes, bro?
-Can I hang this here?
-Put it over there!
When you see it, you'll be stunned!
There's even a college next to it!
Imagine my cakes being sold here
at Woodlands Drive-in.
Do you know what this is? It's a pager.
Can you make calls?
-Who will you talk to?
-It's for you.
Thanks.
-How does it look?
-That hand looks like a bag!
Why don't you draw?
As the planes weight increases,
so will fuel cost.
An airline company in America...
Pay attention!
They cut down 500 pounds
by not painting their flights!
That's four people flying for free!
Don't you like things
that are heavy?
Without an axe, you split me apart!
With spear-headed words,
You pierce my heart!
As you touch me here and there
Your heart's desire, I do hear!
I'm burning hot! I need a love shot!
I'm no touch-me-not,
Delay not, lost in thought!
The mat is spread! The feast is set!
Come to me, the word is said!
Why do you hesitate?
What are you waiting for?
Why this drama? Just take me now!
I've seen your ego! Why don't you let go?
What's bubbling over, is my hidden desire!
Get ready, my love,
It's going to rain fire!
To sum it up, passengers
must be able to buy plane tickets,
like they purchase soaps.
Together, we can make it happen.
That's it. Thank you.
Indian Airlines
itself has a 1,000 crore debt.
And you want to make profits
with 1,000 rupee tickets to Delhi?
My competition is not with
Indian Airlines,
it's with Indian Railways.
Indian Railways?
And the Indian Railways
are doing very well.
A Boeing plane costs
136 crores, Mr. Maaran.
Even a second-hand plane costs 90 crores.
What can you do with just ten crores?
I didn't say I was buying planes.
We'll lease them.
What if your revenue
is less than expected?
At 70% occupancy like most airlines,
we earn 12.42 crores.
That's a profit of 4.14 crores.
Sounds impossible.
-Deeksha?
-He's right.
Taking into consideration...
If it's less than 70% occupancy?
If it's 70% occupancy
at 10,000 rupees per ticket,
won't I get at least 50% occupancy
with 1,000 rupee tickets?
-Little difficult.
-[indistinct chattering]
You are talking way below market rates.
Who will lease Boeing to you
at such low rates?
-PlaneAm.
-Really?
The Twin Tower attack
affected their airline business.
They're willing to give us the planes
at half the price.
Congratulations, Maaran.
They've sanctioned the funds.
Now just get the DGCA license,
and you can launch your airline.
Well done, Maaran.
All thanks to you, sir.
-Oh, no...
-Thanks, sir.
-Just one thing.
-Sir.
Can you have the money ready
to reserve the planes right away?
-You want me to arrange money?
-Yes.
-How much would you need?
-47 lakhs.
It will take us at least six months
to release funds.
If PlaneAm hikes their rates
in the interim,
or if someone else steals this idea,
we'll be in trouble.
Our entire business hinges on this.
Unlicensed planes can't fly into India.
Get them to Malaysia
and start painting and stickering there.
So we can get them to India
once we get the license.
-Good idea. I'll handle this.
-Good.
MULLUM MALARUM
[sniffling]
Folks come here to get loans
for tractors and autos.
You're the first to ask for airplanes!
Alright then.
It's a proud moment
if one of ours starts an airline.
I had a lot of dreams in my youth.
But no one lent me money.
Projected profit
for the first six months...
That's okay. I'm allergic to computers.
-How much, ma'am? 47 lakhs?
-Yes, 47 lakhs.
Check if this loan is feasible.
Don't mistake me.
They need to do some work, right?
Your house and farmlands
are good for 40 lakhs.
They want an excess seven lakhs!
We can't give more...
He's my teacher's son! Give him the money.
Sign this, ma'am.
You're starting a new business
face east and sign.
If you default payment by even a day,
the next three months
you'll pay two-fold interest.
-I'll pay on time...
-That's okay.
Ma'am, please leave.
I'll send the money over.
-What's next?
-Get license from the DGCA.
-What's that?
-Like the RTO office in town?
-We need a license from them to fly.
-We'll get it, right?
Replay the reel from the beginning!
Okay, sir. I'll take care of this.
-[bell dings]
-Why did you give him an appointment?
He was referred by Prakash Babu from SCI.
He's been coming here
for two months.
He should know
meeting the DGCA isn't easy.
-Let him wait.
-Yes, sir.
Sir, you asked me to come at 8:30.
I was here at 7:00, before the peon.
I haven't been called yet.
-Please wait!
-Sir...
-But I was the first appointment...
-Excuse me.
[In Hindi] All of you please leave
and come back after an hour.
Car is ready, sir.
Sir, Maaran. Mr. Prakash Babu reference.
-I'm sorry. You're still here?
-It's alright.
I have an urgent meeting
with the new aviation minister.
-Can we meet tomorrow?
-Sure, sir.
-Nice.
-Thanks.
Bye.
Morning, sir.
-Maaran, I went through your documents.
-Thanks.
-Very interesting.
-Sir.
We can wrap it up tomorrow.
Yeah? No problem, right?
-Sure, sir. I'll wait.
-Nice.
Have you set up a meeting
with the aviation minister?
I spoke to his assistant.
-When is it?
-Tomorrow.
[door opens]
Maaran!
Sir.
We can wrap it up today, right?
He's off for a week.
Didn't you know?
Come back later.
You're his assistant, right?
It's your job to keep him posted, right?
You're a smart guy, right?
I can only say what he tells me to.
How long will you make me wait?
Just for one meeting...
I don't have the time or money for this.
-Please understand.
-Then why do you keep coming?
Maaran, do you know Ratan Tata?
He waited here for 20 years
to start Tata Airlines.
He failed.
And you are a nobody, Mahesh.
Get going. Try to understand.
Don't show up next week!
Either pay the interest
or give your house to Arivu.
Please trust us.
We will pay back your money.
Painting charges ate up all our money!
Just two lakhs left!
All India Radio.
A scientist's amazing journey
from Rameswaram to the Rashtrapati Bhavan.
A special interview
with President Abdul Kalam
by Chitra Ramaswamy,
our Senior Correspondent from Chennai.
[in Hindi] Akashvani.
From Rameswaram to Rashtrapati Bhavan...
Damn! So much security!
-If we get caught, we're doomed!
-We won't.
That stupid bet was a joke.
This isn't like meeting Paresh on a jet!
We can't just sneak in through the door!
I was taught
that if the door is ajar,
don't just get a foot in,
dash in!
I can't lie
to the President, Maaran. Hello.
It's not wrong to lie for a good cause.
-"Falsehood takes on truth's nature..."
-What?
Thiruvalluvar has said so.
The man inside knows it well.
It's not news if I don't meet him.
-But...
-Sir, this way,
-Okay.
-Yes, sir.
But if I do meet him today,
-you get an exclusive headline!
-Shh.
Don't act over smart.
I'm staking everything to do this
only because I'm just another sheep
among a billion here!
And I hope you won't become one.
-You better deliver what you're promising.
-Excuse me, please follow me.
Ma'am, papers please.
One second.
-Sir, this is for...
-Thank you.
Mr. Raghunandan. My voice recordist.
-[detector beeping]
-Sorry.
Just a pen.
By the way, don't quote
Thiruvalluvar to him, please.
You were saying it all wrong!
I'm Chitra Ramaswamy.
This is my voice recordist... Raghunandan,
Raghunandan... Raghunandan...
I'm Chitra Ramaswamy.
-This is my voice recordist Raghunandan.
-This way, please.
Your ID?
Your ID, sir.
We are a team. This is my ID.
I need to see your ID.
Here. I'm Raghunandan, voice recordist.
Your photo ID, please.
We have papers from downstairs.
-No, ma'am! We need a photo ID!
-I'm not from the radio station.
I'm Nedumaaran Rajangam.
I just need two minutes...
-No, sir!
-Please let me see him!
Sir, please... Listen to me... Sir...
If I could've made
a 16-hour trip in two hours,
I would've saved my ailing dad!
I want to start a low-cost airline,
but they won't let me, sir!
-Sir...
-Son...
are you from Madurai?
Yes, sir!
I just need two minutes of your time!
After that if you think I'm wrong,
have me arrested!
-Dhanraj, please let him in.
-Yes, sir!
Security under control.
[indistinct chatter]
Sir...
-Good day, sir.
Good day.
I'm from a small village
near Sholavandhan.
My father was a government school teacher.
Hello.
-Maara!-Mom?
-Mom!-Maara...
Your father has been bedridden
for two weeks now!
He's holding on just to see you!
The doctor says...
he won't survive!
Tell dad I'll be home
tomorrow by 11:00 a.m.
Come home, my boy!
-I'll be there! Be brave!
-Hurry!
-I'll come!
-Come soon!
Oh, God!
-Don't worry!
-This is for the flight fare.
Hurry up! You can catch
the 8:00 p.m. flight!
Will send the money order
as soon as I reach home.
Shut up!
This is 6,000.
Business class costs 11,200.
Economy costs 6,000, right?
Those are fully booked.
Excuse me, sir. Please.
No...
Is there anything you can do?
-I'm sorry. We don't give discounts.
-Is there any cancellation...
-Sir, here you go, with your money.
-Ma'am, but...
-Please move.
-I need this ticket...
Try and understand. Please move aside.
-Ma'am, please...
-Excuse me.
Sir, my dad is unwell. I need to meet him.
I only have 6,000,
-but she's asking me to get first class...
-Please move! They're waiting...
Okay, I'll go get the money!
How much time do I have?
-My, God!
-How much time do I have?
Five minutes.
Excuse me!
-Sir...
-Move now!
When is the next flight?
When is it?
In two days.
Oh, God! The smell.
Please move aside, sir!
Two days!
Sir? Sir... Sir...
My father is unwell.
I need to buy a ticket.
It's an emergency, sir.
When you're flying,
you should bring money. Okay?
Ma'am... Ma'am, if you could
please help me...
Sir? Sir, I need to get this ticket.
-Can you help me with some money?
-Sorry, no.
-Is he mad?
-Crazy people.
Sir?
Ma'am?
My father's dying. It's an emergency.
Boarding is gonna close in five minutes.
I need to go to Madras.
The last plane leaves in five minutes!
Sir? Sir?
Sir, it's an emergency!
My father is very sick.
I don't have money for the ticket.
Please give him some, Dad.
[In Telugu] Keep quiet, Gowtham.
Just shut up and read your comic.
Please lend me some money.
I can give you...
I can give you my gold ring!
I'll give you my address and phone number.
Please understand!
[in Telugu] Security!
What's this nuisance?
Sir, please help me! I can show you my...
I'm an Air Force Officer, batch of '87!
Can somebody understand...
Can someone please help me?
Give me your address and phone number,
and I'll pay you back! I swear!
Please, I need this money!
Boarding is gonna close in five minutes!
I'm Nedumaaran. No. 7...
Ayyanar Sangili Karuppan Kovil Street,
Karupatti,
Sholavandhan, Madurai-625205.
This is my address! Please!
I will come! And I can give you
the money back!
Someone please help!
Sir, please! I need this money
for the ticket.
Sir, please help me! Sir!
Ma'am!
My dad's on his deathbed.
I need to go see him.
Please help me, ma'am!
I don't want to beg,
but I need to be on that plane!
I need to go see my dad!
Someone please help me!
My mother is old and alone.
I need to be there!
I must be on that plane!
I must be on that plane...
[engine sputtering]
[in Telugu] What's wrong?
-[in Telugu] I don't know. Let me check.
-What happened?
SHRI RENUKA YELLAMMATALLI LORRY SERVICES
You've already lost.
And you'll always be a loser.
Who is it?
You taught thousands to write,
but you can only scribble now.
We want the train!
-Kaali!
-I can't open my eye, Maara!
[people crying in distant]
They usually say, "The eldest son
is for the mother
and youngest is for the father."
Being the only son,
you still couldn't come in time.
-Mom.
-Why did you come?
Mom?
Why did you come?
Why the hell did you come?
Why did you come after everything is over?
I can't...
Oh, God!
He loved you so much!
Had you just seen him once
he would've gone peacefully!
He said you wouldn't want
to speak to a loser!
You hung up on him!
Your never did let go of your ego!
Let go of my feet!
They had to cremate him
because he'd been so sick!
A random person did the last rites,
like he was an orphan!
He held on to his breath
hoping that you'd come.
He kept saying
he could see you?
And he died watching the door awaiting you.
-You bloody wretch!
-I'm sorry!
You couldn't even light his pyre!
I didn't have money for the ticket!
You never understood him!
Look at this! Read it!
You are a literate, right? Read them.
Go ahead!
Read them all!
Today, my son left home.
Though obstacles be many,
he will overcome them all!
Look how proud he was of you!
Pick it up!
Look at what he wrote!
He is going to fly
But I know he won't rest
until he makes everyone fly with him!
He knew you so well!
His words are etched here!
They say a sparrow can never aspire
to be an eagle,
but my son will change that!
Isn't this enough? You wretch!
Look how well he knew you!
Dad...
Look at everything!
He always said,Time is the most valuable asset.
-I didn't have money, mom!
-If you didn't come in time,
what's the point
of relationships or money?
Dad!
I'm sorry, Mom!
Forgive me, Mom!
I'll never get angry again.
The next three years at the Air Force,
I had just one thought...
To make the common man fly.
Why did you go to the President?
I could've done this for you.
Anyway, all the best.
Move round and round
Like a surging hurricane!
Lunge far and wide
Like a bull off its leash!
Keep the act alive! Rock the damn house!
Like the blazing sun,
Set your path on fire!
Mr. Balaiyya!
When aviation is so down,
you're expanding your airlines!
The new aviation minister,
Mr. Nakul Patel,
says he'll give no handouts.
What do you think about this?
Hey, Trivedi!
One must take risks to win!
I need no handouts.
My beer company is enough to bail me out!
-[reporters clamoring]
-Hey, Paresh!
-What is this aero show?
-A flight exhibition, uncle!
Like our town fair!
-Is our plane here?
-I'll bring them in from Malaysia!
We got our license!
-Let's go closer!
-When are our planes arriving?
It'll be here in a week, sir.
-Hi, Balaiyya.
-Paresh!
Expanding your flights, huh?
I can't take risks like you, my friend.
No.
I came to check out turboprops for cargo.
Our planes await us at Malaysia.
There's Paresh!
Why did Prakash Babu
bring that halfwit here?
Teacher and student.
Oh, so he's that guy!
He looks like a nice chap.
So obviously, he's doomed!
Let's sit back and enjoy.
You know a bumblebee, Balaiyya?
It's not designed aerodynamically.
Yet, it flies all the time.
Do you know why?
Because it doesn't know that it can't fly!
Make sure he learns that now.
[pager beeps]
Bommi, check.
Che says, "Call me".
-Our planes are leaving, Maara!-What?
PlaneAm cancelled our deal!
They're taking them back in three days!
Why? What happened?
The Indian DGCA is asking them
for Boeing blueprints!
Hundreds of Boeings fly in India!
No one has asked them for blueprints!
PlaneAm told us
to check with our government.
PlaneAm's levied a 50 lakh fine
for blocking their flights.
Why is our government targeting us?
Maara!
Pay up, sir!
I'll pay.
I'll take an auto rickshaw!
The new bylaw was passed last week.
-Didn't you know?
-Will Boeing give their blueprints?
Will any company
reveal their trade secrets?
How can you change rules suddenly?
Calm down, Mr. Nedumaaran.
Laws can't be changed for you.
But you will for the rich?
I'm running out of money.
That's not my problem.
It's your headache.
The DGCA has just done its job.
-Stop messing with me!
-Watch your words!
Why you want to build an airline?
-Go home and graze your cows
-What? Hey!
Go pimp for Jaz Air!
I can break your damn neck!
I'm being patient
and you keep fucking with me!
Let him go, Maaran!
Sir.
-Sir!
-Hey, Maaran
I've been trying for days to see you!
They've changed the laws
and asking for blueprints.
PlaneAm is ending the deal
and demanding a penalty of 50 lakhs...
We'll lose our planes!
If you could loan me 50 lakhs...
647.38 crores.
No, sir. I only asked for 50 lakhs.
Sir.
That's Mr. Paresh's income
from his travel agency alone.
Every year.
And you want him to join you
and destroy his own business.
Would he let that go?
Don't you still get it?
Paresh is the main angel investor of SCI!
And he controls us all.
Prakash.
Look how easily he crushed you.
Yes, that's Paresh!
By the time you settle your debt,
you'll be finished.
But your idea is fantastic!
This never occurred to us!
Check that out.
Your PlaneAm aircraft.
We can break and make laws in a day.
He spent just ten minutes
on you
and you're in serious trouble.
Don't make him think more!
Good luck.
Paresh!
Where the hell is Paresh?
Where is Paresh!
Spineless thug!
Bloody bastard!
[screaming]
Didn't I tell you he would ruin your life?
How can I relax
with you married to this nut?
Only God can save him now!
How long will he live off you?
Are you getting it?
Our community will humiliate us!
The cow's been mooing all day!
Go check, you moron!
You don't own a cow!
She's talking about me.
Here! I came to give you this!
An arrogant shrew
with a worthless husband.
Here. You keep your saree.
Take your mother and leave!
Some daughter, she is a witch.
Put the cake down.
Her husband is a loser.
Let's go.
-The bags?
-Shut up and come!
[airplane whooshing]
You haven't eaten all day!
I didn't see you come in.
When did you come?
Maara...
Seenu uncle from next door came by.
His kids want to join
a tutorial center for IAS exams.
He feels you would teach them better.
What do you say?
They're smart kids!
It'll take your mind off this.
Uncle said he'd pay you.
I knew it.
I knew you would eventually get there.
Get where, Maara?
You're pointing out that I'm
living off of you, right?
Did I say that?
How much did Seenu uncle offer
to help you out?
Your mom was right
about you blabbing when you get hungry.
Hey!
Stop treating me like an idiot!
Your mom was at least direct.
Why are you fighting with me?
Let's figure out your next move.
Oh, yeah, I must figure that out.
I wonder why that didn't
occur to this dimwit!
Enlighten me
on how to run an airline, baker girl.
Go ahead.
I'm all ears.
Every time you met investors
with your idea,
they laughed you out of the room.
To them, your idea
was just a damn cupcake.
And what you demean
puts food on our table.
Despite my family's objections,
I married you!
I believed you'd make the poor fly!
Was it all just talk!
Weren't you serious at all!
Make it happen!
Never figured you for a loser, Maara!
Why do you want to live with a loser?
Get lost!
Go away!
Achieve something and then get macho!
Fucking ego!
My love!
Oh, love of my life!
Bommi.
Like tiny fireflies,
You shone bright and faded away!
Like an elusive bird, you simply vanished!
I want you to spread roots
And render the shade of the neem!
In the comfort of your shadow,
I need to rest!
My heart has wilted...
-Hey, did Bommi come by?
-No.
Rush forth as a spring
And fill my life with life!
Four minutes!
The four minutes I couldn't see you
When I couldn't see you
My entire being shriveled into a dot!
A dot, I became!
Where will I go, Maara?
This is my home.
My only home.
Oh, love of my life!
I looked for you everywhere!
I would have kept you running for days...
if I wasn't pregnant.
Who breaks such news like this?
Can't you talk like a normal person?
I can't. This is who I am!
Only then it gets
into your thick skull, right?
-[birds chirping]
-[wings flapping]
Bommi.
[chirping and flapping continues]
To hell with the net...
Damn those sparrows.
They never eat.
The bigger birds will eat it all
and leave them hungry.
A sparrow is neither too big
nor flies too high.
So it needs very less food.
What, Maara?
For its size,
and the height it flies,
it doesn't need much food.
So...
Not much fuel.
Small planes. A first in India.
Bommi, small planes need less fuel.
So tickets can be even cheaper.
First time in India,
I'm going to convert cargo planes
to passenger ones.
We are leaders
when it comes to small planes.
Our turboprops are the best in the market.
But large planes
have replaced turboprops everywhere.
Your planes are used
only for cargo transport.
I'll make your aircraft
passenger planes. Joint venture.
What is this "tur-bur" you speak of?
"Turboprops", uncle!
They're like the small Maruti 800 cars.
They only fly half as high as big planes.
But fuel costs also get halved.
Won't they be cramped?
Yes, the planes are small.
But they will also get full
with just 70 people.
Large planes
need 200 passengers to get full.
Therefore, low costs and high profits!
You want us to give our planes
to you for free or what?
Every day 7,500 trains
operate in my country,
That's 2.5 crore passengers a day.
Plus, there are several private
and government bus services.
If just 2% of these people
fly in our airline,
we can make crores in revenues.
Can't fly too far with turboprops, sir.
We can't do prestige routes
like Chennai to Delhi.
Should it be a non-stop to Delhi?
We'll have stops at Vijayawada
and Nagpur and voila!
We cover big cities and small towns!
That's the strength of a sparrow!
If we share costs with Turboprop company,
in a joint venture...
-four crores will suffice!
-Super, sir.
Tea bill, 800 bucks, is still due!
It's about to rain millions
and you're asking for 800 bucks!
-Get lost!
-Yeah, right!
You can't even pay 800,
but building castles in air.
-I'll take these with me.
-Very well.
I listened to you and set up shop here,
I was worried it wouldn't take off.
I expected 300-400 bucks tops,
but I make over a 1,000.
A thousand?
Per week?
No! Per day!
The college girls across the road
come by every day,
and the boys follow them
in like puppy dogs!
My shop is in the right place!
Whose idea was that?
Shall we go?
Not bad, Maara.
I thought you were the only one
who followed girls to bakeries!
But most boys are, too.
Isn't it time for work?
Let's eat. I've ordered fritters.
I'm really hungry.
A coffee, bro.
Lots of sugar.
Okay, madam.
-No, thanks.
-What's wrong?
Paresh isn't in India this month.
We must get in our planes secretively
before he returns.
How?
Ground work and feasibility reports
are done.
I even had a meeting
with a French company.
If we get this done,
we'll be up and running!
We don't even need eight crores,
just four crores will do.
So why wait? Start!
We can!
But only after the company is registered,
we can take off.
Bommi...
Can you lend me 15,000?
Because... I...
-Is that my coffee? Lots of sugar?
-Indeed.
-For registration...
-Give me the bill.
Just pay the registration fee.
I can finalize the deal.
I'll succeed this time.
I'll repay you in three months.
I'll keep accounts.
You keep track of it, too.
No, I...
Good day, sir.
Maara...
not just fifteen,
I'll give you twenty thousand
You always talk
of doing great things
so act accordingly.
Why this false pride with me?
Sorry.
Why is it so hard for you
to ask your wife for help?
I've said this already!
My bakery is yours
and your airline is mine.
Isn't that our deal?
One fresh juice for the boss lady!
Bhawar?
Hey!
-Yes, sir!
-How?
You're a goddamn pauper.
How can you sleep so peacefully?
Brother, come.
Something is not right.
Is there a problem?
Relax, Paresh.
All is well.
Just a small glitch with turboprops.
We'll sort it tomorrow. Okay?
How many times have I told you?
Good news can wait,
but tell me the bad news right away!
The planes that we wanted for cargo
have been blocked
as passenger planes by someone.
Ask Mirza to talk.
And if they do not agree, make them agree!
Isn't passenger transport
a better offer for them?
Pay them more than what we promised!
They're not interested!
Call Ananth!
It's 3:00 a.m., Paresh!
[in Gujarati] So? I'm awake!
Why should he sleep?
What is this?
Damn!
It's a joint venture.
Between Turboprop International
and NCS Aviation Private Limited.
Registered in the name of Ms. Sundari.
With Turboprop in the forefront,
he stayed hidden and sealed the deal!
I signed off without a second thought
as only you've been dealing
with Turboprops.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry, Paresh.
He's not rich like Balaiyya.
He's just a fool!
He'll run away
with his tail between his legs!
Balaiyya is the fool.
Once his father's wealth is gone,
he'll disappear!
Bhawar, you call up whoever, wherever,
but finish him.
Don't be hasty, Paresh.
The CBI is still investigating
what we did last time.
I don't care.
His plane
must not land here, Ananth. Okay?
Okay.
Damn villager.
Yes. That's what he is!
Not him, me.
India must only speak
of my story from rags to riches.
There should be
only one Paresh in India. Right?
No one knows you here, buddy!
But everyone seems to know the witch!
-How are you?
-I'm good!
How are you, brother?
-I was just praising you!
-Yeah, I heard.
-Take care of the bakery, uncle!
-Sure.
Make fun of me all you want,
I'll still cook a feast for you!
-Come and eat.
-Sure!
My sister is getting married.
Just a minute, son-in-law!
Come here.
Leave.
Money is the problem, right?
Yes. Why?
Don't worry. That's no problem at all.
Who much?
I meant "how much" in English?
I... I can handle it.
Why do you hesitate to ask me?
Just a minute.
Here you go. It's money too.
What's the matter?
There is 11,528 rupees!
My life savings.
Take it all and get things going!
Happy?
Don't tell Bommi about this,
she'll rip me apart!
-Uncle Alapparai.
-Quit laughing!
It's for all of you. Split it up equally!
We need 3.25 crores.
About 2,000 times what you've given us.
Three crores?
I don't even know how many zeroes it has.
This is all I have.
Please don't mistake me.
Won't this be enough?
It's not that, uncle?
Uncle!
Your heart is much bigger
than a mere three crores!
I don't have much...
Keep it safe.
-Please come.
-Sir.
As a bank manager, I should've called
the Income Tax Department first.
Sir... How much, sir?
See for yourself.
One and a half lakhs. Twenty thousand.
One lakh. Ten thousand. Five hundred.
Your account has been receiving
deposits all day from Sholavandhan!
-Can I... make a call?
-Yeah.
Sure.
Sholavandhan Post?
-Maara's on the line!
-[all clamoring]
Maara, I sent two lakhs to your account.
Did you get it?
Munuswamy brother...
How did you raise so much?
-I pledged my land with Arivu.
-Give me the phone.
I pushed my sister's wedding for a bit!
The groom will wait until you repay!
-You keep going!
-You...
You should've told me!
Why did you go to that bloodsucking Arivu?
We can't be bystanders and see you
work hard to make our lives better.
It's because you stopped the train,
our land prices have skyrocketed!
-Let me speak to Maaran!
-Go on!
I sold all my paddy and sent 8,000 rupees.
Did you get it?
I did.
-Yes, he got it!
-Give it to him!
-Here you go!
-Calm down!
Maara, my boy...
Grandpa...
I just plant chilies
as there were no rains.
I could only send 500 rupees.
Did you get it?
You're struggling without rain...
Why did you do it?
This kid wants to talk to you!
Talk to him! Here you go! Talk!
-Hello?-Selvi?
Uncle Maara,
did you get my money?
How did you get so much money?
From my piggy bank.
Take me in your airplane, too.
Make your donations right away!
Stand in line. Don't cut in.
All of you who chipped in,
please eat and go.
Thirty seven thousand. Twelve thousand.
Forty thousand. Thirty one thousand.
Look properly! It's 31 lakhs.
Lakhs?
Get the airplanes here real soon, Maara!
I will fly all our people
to my daughter's wedding!
No, sir. Let's first get back
your lands from Arivu.
I'll come talk to him myself.
Maara...
Mom?
If you're the teacher's son,
I'm his wife.
I demanded the documents back from Arivu.
He told us to pay up
six months interest anyway.
No one can touch us if we're united!
Victory or defeat,
it's all in your hands now!
You'll win, right?
Your father is always with you.
We're all praying for you, son!
Win.
We're counting on you. Win!
Don't cry! He'll win!
Victory is yours.
-Shall I hang up?
-Okay, Mom.
All major airports
are under Paresh's control.
You'll land your planes
in these airstrips?
Indeed. Built in the British era.
Airstrips used for postal delivery
and diplomatic trips.
Nehru and Kamaraj have been here.
Abandoned unused airstrips?
How many are there? Two or three?
Five hundred!
Five hundred of these exist across India.
We'll prep them for our planes to land!
The sky belongs to us all!
Let us bide our time to get hold of it!
Let's dispense with the phonies
And kick out the shams!
Let's build some iron wings
And take to the stars!
Those who call this a fool's errand
Just admitted to being fools!
They show up first in line to kiss up
When victory is at hand!
Those who call this a fool's errand
Just admitted to being fools!
They show up first in line to kiss up
When victory is at hand!
The sky is very near!
Let us jump up without fear!
It isn't too far off!
As we get closer, the dream grows nearer!
What are you saying? Be clear.
For the first time, Indians can book
air tickets with credit cards.
How many Indians have credit cards?
They all have telephones, right?
They can call our call center
and book tickets.
With a PNR number
they can pick up tickets
at their bank or supermarket.
But...
We are trying this
with publicly owned computers.
Interworld spends six months
just testing this software!
We don't have that kind of luxury.
No one else has tried this here before.
So this is a first in India.
You want to sell your tickets
at the railway counter?
Why will I agree
to you taking away my business.
You find 10000 people in waiting list
for AC coaches every day.
I'll take only those people in my airline.
Just give me a small space
next to your reservation counter.
Bottom line is,
they need to travel, right?
Alright. It's a great idea!
All the very best, Mr. Maaran.
You're never too old
To stop chasing the moon, my friend!
Chase your dreams
And there are no worries, dear comrade!
Even if you lose, the world will not mind!
Stand by and do nothing?
It will never respect you!
If the battle rages on
With even no small victories
Won't it change one day
To a celebration sans failures?
BISMI MOBILES
SALES & SERVICES
No one else can live your life...
-Call for you!
-What is it called?
The company is called Deccan Air.
Do you like it?
He is medically unfit.
-Unfit?
-Yes.
You bugger off. You come in!
It isn't too far off!
As we get closer, the dream grows nearer!
Deccan Air won't get pilots.
We paid them three times more
than Maaran did.
They took it!
Dismiss all of them next month.
Brother?
If I can buy them...
anybody can buy them.
Maara is here!
The pilots didn't show up!
-Seby!
-Where is he off to?
-Do you get anything he does?
-Maara, come soon!
Where are you going?
None of our pilots came!
A guy who can buy a government
can buy anyone.
There are our pilots.
Retired military aviators
who flew fighter jets for India.
There is an age limit! How will this work?
Let me in on the joke!
Air Force pilots retire at 57,
civilian pilots retire at 61.
They can fly for another four years!
Kickass! Two can play this game.
We aren't Madurai folk for nothing.
Captain Rajiv Manohar,
he coordinated all this.
Retired as Air Commodore.
I don't believe this.
Is this how it is done!
-We need to focus on the airline, uncle!
-Yes, yes!
What brings you to the office, boss?
A proposal.
What proposal?
A business proposal!
What business?
Do you embrace all your
vendors like this?
Let my catering division
take care of your in-flight snacks.
Logistically impossible
with just one outlet in Madras.
It is possible!
Who told you Madras was my only base?
I have franchises!
Che's family in Vijayawada.
My brother is in Madurai.
Projected monthly turnovers ten lakhs!
That's 1.2 crores per year!
Welcome to Deccan Air, Sundari Nedumaaran!
Don't expect
any special treatment. Alright?
You too, don't expect any discounts. Deal.
We're talking business!
Business is done, right?
It's coming!
What's he up to?
What's this? I don't understand!
Like we get everything you say.
When our planes land for the first time
it would be auspicious
to land facing east.
You won't get it! Back off!
No! They'll land only as per
the designated coordinates!
There you go again!
Never clear.
That's ours, right?
Look, uncle! Our plane is coming!
Chennai Tower, this is Deccan Air 582.
Minimum fuel.
Requesting landing clearance.
Go around, Deccan Air 582.
Where are the other two planes?
Hence the three garlands?
They'll come in two days.
Why aren't they landing?
They are not getting permission to land?
Is there a problem with DA 582 landing?
It's huge! Garlands are small, damn!
-Maara...
-How long will they circle around?
Get to the ATC, boys!
I'll handle the ground operations!
-Seby, hurry up!
-Go!
-I need to go too, uncle!
-Wait!
-Let go! Why is he running?
-You're pregnant. Don't run!
I said we have
a fuel emergency, goddammit!
I say again, Deccan Air 582, go around.
There is something wrong, Captain.
They're ignoring protocol."
Chennai Tower,
requesting reason for denial!
I say this again,
go around, Deccan Air 582!
Paresh,
this is highly risky.
Keep this up and that plane will crash!
You said you just wanted to scare them!
You're using civil aviation property
to blackmail him!
I'll be the one investigated!
How dare you?
You are not dumb enough
to piss off the man
who put you in the DGCA, are you?
You owe me, my friend!
Paresh...
we'll be in trouble if it crashes.
Stop this, Paresh! Enough!
Che, do you copy?
Tambaram Air Force. Runway 1-5.
Land there!
Do you have enough fuel for that?
I'll handle it!
Switch to our company frequency!
Who the hell are you
to give the instructions?
I own that fucking plane!
Let's go!
Guards! Guards, take him out!
Go! Go! Go!
Che, listen, if the fuel is low,
switch to auxiliary engines!
Don't teach me how to do my job!
My dad always warned me
not to hang out with you.
I should've listened!
If anything happens to me,
tell Preethi I love her.
I'll tell that Brigadier's daughter, too.
Bring our plane home safely, man.
Keep going.
Come in, Che!
-Che?
-[siren wailing]
Get help!
-He'll be okay, right?
-Open the emergency hatch! Hurry!
Sir, we are ex-Air Force officers...
We are ex-Air Force officers!
There are two pilots inside!
They need some help!
We're batch of '87!
There are two officers in there!
Help them!
Please help them! It's an...
[groaning]
Maara!
[indistinct chatter]
Captain!
Jai Hind, sir!
Why didn't you declare Mayday
and land at Chennai Airport?
If we had declared Mayday,
they would've impounded
my flights for months!
That's what they want.
My launch is on August 25th.
And it must happen!
Excuse me, sir! Jai Hind, sir!
Call for you, sir.
The airport authorities
want an update for the press!
Three years ago, a Saudia Boeing
made an emergency landing.
On this very airstrip!
-Remember, Chaitanya?
-Sir.
What did we do?
We investigated for terrorist links.
And then we levied a five-crore fine.
You three will get a ten-year prison term
along with the fine.
You haven't even taken off,
but you already have enemies
all over the country.
My investigation is done.
They aren't terrorists at all.
Tell them I'm letting them go!
They'll pay a fine!
-Dismiss!
-Jai Hind, sir!
You will pay a fine!
For the unauthorized landing on our base,
the fine is 25,000!
You can pay three months after
you start your airline.
What are you waiting for?
A hug and a sendoff ceremony?
Go.
-Buzz off!
-Sir!
Maara.
They'll target you for letting me go.
Do I look scared?
You never liked me, sir.
Maara...
If I had not punished you back then
my cadets wouldn't have respected me.
And if I bow to political pressure now,
I won't respect myself.
[in Telugu] Kid...
what you intend to do...
is much bigger than either of our egos.
A soldier must ensure
to bring every trooper home.
Like you did today.
You are a true leader.
Leader!
I don't smoke.
You shouldn't either.
You're getting old, right?
Hey!
[in Telugu] Don't you dare call me old!
Get out before I change my mind.
Get lost!
Mr. Maaran! Ready to fly, huh?
Are you inviting the minister? Good.
Need a recommendation?
Do you know Tata? Ratan Tata?
He himself couldn't start an airline here.
Poor guy tried for 20 years!
-Twenty years...
-You think you can scare me?
Going on and on about Ratan Tata!
I'm not Ratan Tata, damn it!
People trust me.
That's more than enough.
People?
Public opinion?
That changes every week!
Be careful, Mr. Maaran.
Excuse me.
I have an airline to run, my friend.
It's my time now.
The people are with him.
You keep swatting this bee
but it continues to fly.
Murthy?
-Murthy!
-Sir!
It's Marudhu, sir.
Right, Marudhu!
Marudhu...
Do you know Nedumaaran Rajangam?
I do, sir.
What do you know?
I heard he's offering
plane tickets at low price.
You'll make people fly for just one-rupee?
Impossible!
Today, 75% of flights fly half-empty!
I'll charge a rupee for each empty seat.
Just a rupee for those who book
much in advance in my airlines.
Once those are booked,
500 rupee seats open up!
Then, the 1,000s!
But aren't you deceiving people
by giving just ten one rupee tickets?
Three planes. Ten trips each per day.
That is 300 people will fly
at one-rupee, per day.
And even our most expensive ticket
costs the same as a train ticket.
Will you go in that plane?
I don't know if I will, sir.
But I want my mother to fly
at least once.
She'll love it.
There are two unused airstrips
in your region.
Imagine the impact
when these planes land there!
So my servant will fly with me
as an equal?
And I'm supposed to let that happen?
His investment.
That must be destroyed first.
We're proud to cover
the launch of this airline
that could be a significant milestone
in the history of Indian aviation...
Back in the day, I told the teacher
his son would fly.
And he has!
I hereby announce two airstrips
will be operated in my region alone!
I've always been a visionary.
We must encourage the youth of our nation.
I declare Deccan Air launched!
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls,
you're welcome onboard,
Deccan Air maiden flight.
We're now ready for departure.
Enjoy our services. Thank you.
[indistinct announcement over PA]
Deccan Air 582, ready for departure.
Line up and clear for take-off. Wind calm.
[engine sputtering]
Fire!
-Fire! Get up!
-Go! Go!
[all clamoring]
Where? Where is it?
Please sit!
-[indistinct screaming]
-Please stay calm!
There's smoke in engine one!
Stay calm!
Where are you going?
Please stay calm! Captain!
Captain, smoke!
Captain, smoke! Abort!
-Captain! Captain!
-[alarm beeping]
Reject take-off! Power lever idle!
[all clamoring]
Come on! Apply brakes, Captain!
Applying maximum brakes!
Deccan Air 582, Chennai Tower!
Mayday! Mayday! Engine smoke.
Evacuate! Evacuate! Evacuate!
Evacuate! Go! Go!
Come along, sir!
What is this?
Steer clear of the aircraft!
Stay back! Move away!
Relax, sir. Please wait in the lounge.
I'll set things right.
How much longer, Che?
Forty-five minutes! I'm on it!
Just give me some time!
Sir... I'll get everything alright...
This is a failure! Drive!
Sir, please don't say that!
-Drive!
-Sir... Sir...
Please wait, sir!
-Sir...
-[siren wailing]
His problem is he aims too high!
Will anyone pledge fertile land?
Our lands are going up in smoke!
Shut up, Esakki! Or I'll kill you!
You shut up!
Guys! Guys! Guys!
Nedumaaran is here! Come on!
[reporters clamoring]
What's the cause of the accident?
We need an answer!
The first trip, with a minister on board,
ended in disaster!
Your cheap tickets will claim lives.
It was not our intention.
Did you not follow safety regulations?
As per the international regulations,
Deccan Air...
-Answer us, Maaran!
-People deserve the truth!
-Are you scared to answer?
-Answer us!
-Why are you silent?
Speak up!
Is human life worth so little to you?
How is this fair?
Mr. Maaran, I'm talking to you.
-Answer my question!
-I'm explaining that.
[groaning]
[reporters clamoring]
I'll handle this!
You handle them!
Uncle, let's...
Is it true you did not follow
safety regulations?
Sir, as per international regulations,
we did C&D checks in India and France!
Our goal was low-priced airlines,
not undermining safety.
India has so many basic issues!
Is flying a necessity?
Every benefit must reach everyone!
And they will!
This is my domain.
And I want to break the barriers here!
Is that wrong?
These philosophies are good, Maaran!
Hear me out!
We did all due diligence!
No rules were violated!
-Yeah.
-Stop, sir!
[reporters clamoring]
People are not about to get into
one of these flights in a hurry.
People will not fly Deccan Air again.
This may well be their last flight.
The teacher is back!
[oil trickling]
Are we contesting elections?
Good enough if people fly.
Yeah, we're clear for morning departure.
So shall we issue a CRS?
Yeah. Go check!
Has the oil been uplifted, Che?
They've assigned Bay 64 to us.
Mr. Rajiv Manohar.
Your statement says that
Deccan Air violated many safety rules.
Can you please elaborate?
What crimes
did Deccan Air commit? Tell us.
Is it true
that Deccan Air was indifferent?
No, sir.
This is all my fault.
What's this, sir?
He keeps changing his statement!
Did someone force you
to sabotage Deccan Air's flight?
I was negligent during fueling.
I didn't do my safety checks properly.
It's my fault.
Is someone threatening you?
We all know who is threatening whom.
Please explain that, Mr. Manohar.
Who is threatening you?
He already answered it.
I'm satisfied with his statement.
It's okay.
Deccan Air is not at fault.
File the report as Pilot Negligence.
It was not a technical failure.
Deccan Air is cleared of all charges.
I trusted you, Captain.
I have many financial problems at home.
Worse than mine?
They'll try to buy us, sir.
Saying no is our only strength!
But I...
I won't ask you to leave.
Why the fuck did you let him off?
He's my father's age.
Monday 9:00 p.m., an exclusive interview
with Paresh Goswami.
-Don't miss it!
-Maara.
Why won't you pick up the phone
or charge the damn thing?
Balaiyya wants to meet you tomorrow!
I'm not going.
-It could be useful to us.
-Yes.
I don't want his help!
The shape we're in,
we need all the help we can get.
I'm not going to do business
with such people.
I'm taking the evening bus home.
You just got here this morning.
Stay the night!
No, buddy... I just came by to see you.
My sister's fiance's family
asking for a wedding date.
Don't stress. Whenever you say!
Just indicate a date,
and I'll manage the rest.
See you. Bye, Bommi!
Let's go, Kadhir.
See you, buddy.
See you.
Not one interview of yours is here.
Deccan Air, which announced
one-rupee ticket
a question mark dangles
on its future.
The people's faith in Deccan Air...
Running an airline is not a game!
No wonder it tanked!
Airplanes are for the rich!
Not for people like us!
Paresh Goswami questions
if the DGCA enquiry commission was bribed.
Even our advertisement has been buried!
They play with our feelings
and royally screw us!
No one is listening to us!
Due to safety issues,
Deccan Air has come to an end.
They broke people's trust in us.
A plane, Maara! Come on! Race!
Maara.
Welcome.
Come have a drink.
No, we're good.
Go ahead, have a drink, man. Have fun!
Okay, I'll get to the point.
Why do we need two airlines?
I'll merge your company with mine.
Who will fly in our planes then?
Only the rich, of course!
My team said a maximum of twelve crores.
But I'll give you fifteen crores!
Guys, do we have a deal?
Okay. Sixteen crores, then!
Maaran, you better take it
before I change my mind.
Give us two minutes.
We'll discuss and get back to you.
Okay.
Maara... Let's think it over, Maara.
I already have.
No.
Why are you taking a risk?
It's a great offer. Take it!
Sometimes I get doubts
about my airline's success.
But the way you're lusting after it.
my doubts are all gone.
Come on. You've no business sense.
You can't survive a day here
without my support.
I don't understand you guys.
You won't.
You're a socialite. I'm a socialist.
We are nothing alike.
Imbecile!
Let's go!
-Did he call me an imbecile?
-Yes, sir.
How can you decide alone?
Don't you need to discuss it with us?
I quit my job because of you!
Is that nothing to you?
You call this a partnership?
You'll bring all of us to the streets?
-Che...
-What's your problem?
-Tell me!
-Back off, Che!
You're crazy!
Think about us too.
We all are in deep shit.
Seby has a family to feed!
My dad cut me off when I quit my job!
Aren't we human beings too!
Who can stick with you?
Is your wife happy at least?
-[both grunting]
-Hit me!
Go on, hit me!
Don't hit the bellies of the villagers
relying on you!
Am I? That dog inside doesn't get it!
Don't you, too!
By turning him down,
we make a billion Indians fly one day!
Why are we doing this!
Don't you know what he's bargaining for?
Our dream! Don't you understand?
How much did he offer?
Sixteen crores.
Did you take it?
I let down our family, Bommi.
Did you poison the food?
I would have, if you had sold out.
This is a small show on All India Radio.
It will do, ma'am.
It's the language of my people.
I'll talk to the new FM stations as well.
They're growing. You'll get a wider reach.
Ready?
Five, four, three, two, one.
Go.
Sir.
We look at the skies with awe,
but wouldn't dare dream
of seeing the world from up there.
People felt the same way
in my village too.
But today, we've risen too
and come to fly.
Goswami is afraid of sub-standard people
entering the industry.
Yes. He is terrified of us.
But not for the reasons he claims.
He knows very well
that our airline passed every safety test
as his airlines did.
So, what does he fear?
He fears that those beneath him
will rise to his level.
The rich want the poor to remain poor.
A century ago, they claimed
electricity was only for the rich.
Fifty years ago,
they said the same about the cars.
Who are they to decide?
Because others should not
enjoy this except them.
We spend days to go from place to place.
But the rich...
They fly like Gods above us!
If we level with them,
no one will be beneath them.
That's what he fears!
You can now book plane tickets
over the phone!
We will give you a PNR number.
Just show the number
at your bank or post office.
Why do small towns remain small?
Why haven't they grown?
If we want to grow,
sometimes we must walk
sometimes, we must run,
and sometimes, we have to fly!
That is called as air connectivity.
My airline promises
air connectivity to everyone.
Our planes will reach every small town!
Not only Chennai, every place will grow.
Won't that scare the privileged?
The Question with Amit Trivedi.
-Thank you for joining us on The Question.
-Thank you
Let's talk about
what's on everyone's mind,
"Low-cost aviation."
Your thoughts, sir?
Look, Mr. Amit.
When flying in an aluminum can
at 1,000km/hr,
what will be on your mind?
-Safety?
-Exactly!
That safety requires
all kinds of testing and security!
It's expensive, but it is a must!
When someone offers to lower that price,
people must think hard.
They have a point, sir.
How can one feel safe at such low prices?
I have a question for Goswami on safety.
His first class tickets
cost three times more than economy.
If there was an accident
would he guarantee thrice the safety
to first class passengers?
But I will guarantee you this.
The Deccan Air pilots
flew fighter jets for India Air force.
Who can fly you safer than them?
Here is why we are afraid
of Nedumaaran entering airline business.
Shoddy equipment.
Retired pilots,
sub-standard products,
he brings in many dangers
like that.
The enquiry commission
cleared us of all charges.
I have no money to bribe them.
I won't pay bribes
with my people's hard-earned money.
If money was my priority,
I'd have made millions ages ago.
Or I'd gladly tend to my home and child.
Because my wife is very successful.
You talk of so many obstacles...
Why do you go on?
My father wanted electricity
in our village. We got it.
He wanted the train to stop.
And it happened.
And I want the benefits of modern science
to reach everyone.
I want to break the cost barrier
and the damn caste barrier too!
That's why our tickets cost one-rupee.
Not because of low quality.
When flying on a legacy airline like Jaz,
you're completely assured of safety.
As we have a well-trained crew
and the best infrastructure,
our ticket prices will be higher!
But...
Maaran is stripping away all this
and offering cheap tickets!
Tell me something.
is your life worth
the same as half a cup of tea?
My flights are safe.
All I'll say this to those who don't trust
our safety report.
This is my own safety test!
The three people I love the most
will be on Deccan's first flights.
My mother Pechi.
My wife Sundari.
And my daughter Ammu.
Giving airlines to such people
is akin to giving guns
to the mentally ill!
This must be nipped in the bud!
It's very scary!
Listen to him some more
and even I'll believe him.
[reporters clamoring]
-Maara!
We've been trying to reach you!
What happened?
My cell battery is also dead, I guess.
You've not slept in three days.
You'll go crazy this way.
How can I sleep?
He could do anything to our planes.
We need to guard them.
Maara.
What's up, Nedumaaran?
Only Goswami has friends or what?
Don't we have friends?
We never let down our comrades!
Go get some rest!
I have this covered!
Boys, position!
[all] Yes, sir!
Take care of the wingtip clearance.
All in position at Bay 63?
...traveling flight DA 581,
please proceed to gate number two.
I repeat, all passengers
traveling to Thoothukudi
on flight DA 581,
please proceed to gate number two.
-Are we ready for boarding?
-Yes, Captain.
-Luggage tractors can go there, right?
-Yeah.
Welcome, Captain.
Welcome aboard.
It's faster to get to Madurai by bus!
Why is it that
only our plane is parked so far away?
No matter where they throw us,
our plane will fly.
Hello, ma'am.
-Go on.
-Good day, ma'am.
Sir.
We're really happy
to have you on board, ma'am.
There are no passengers?
There's still time, ma'am.
They'll come, won't they?
They will.
This is the last and final call
for passengers traveling from Chennai
to Thoothukudi on flight DA 581,
which is set to take off in a few minutes.
I repeat, this is the last and final call
for passengers traveling to Thoothukudi
on flight DA 581.
Cheer up! We'll handle it!
It's doubtful if people
will risk their lives and fly Deccan Air.
People will reject such an unsafe airline.
And yes, it does look like
the end for Deccan Air.
Our flight has been cancelled, Captain.
People didn't believe me, Bommi.
Let's go.
Airplanes are for the rich!
Not for people like us!
They play with our feelings
and royally screw us!
You're out of your league.
Go home and graze your cows!
Giving airlines to such people
is akin to giving guns
to the mentally ill.
Wow! He remembers the villagers plight!
Thought you'd forgot
as you were busy reproducing!
We are all praying for you, my son!
You should win!
We are all counting on you. Win!
He spent just ten minutes
on you...
and you're in deep trouble.
Maara!
I'm sorry! I screwed up!
You trusted me!
-Forget it!
-I messed up!
We tried. That's what matters.
We came so close and screwed up!
I messed up the Chennai ticket booking.
What are you saying?
Be clear!
The Chennai flight tickets
were not confirmed from our end!
A software glitch caused
all booked tickets to get cancelled!
That's why none of our passengers came
despite booking tickets!
Maara!
They were unable to board our flight!
I'm sorry!
The problem was in the software!
People didn't lose faith in us!
Thousands of our tickets were sold!
It's not that people didn't believe us,
The flights from Madurai to Chennai
and Vijayawada to Chennai,
they were fully booked.
The other planes were 100% occupied.
We won, Maara!
Your love brought the skies
Within our grasp!
This will live on, even when time is gone!
As tears filled our eyes
As scorched fields put up a fight,
A thousand flowers now in sight!
Time to smile, son!
Even a dried-up well with milk, can swell!
Even from a bitter herb, honey can flow!
Under the hot summer sky
A gentle drizzle floats by
As it falls on parched throats,
The town entire float...
-Maara!
-Grandma!
I'm so happy to have flown
in your airplane today!
I've dreamt for years to fly.
Even my son couldn't make it happen.
But today, with my own savings
I flew all the way here! How about that!
See you, son. Let's go!
Buddy...
Time to smile, son!
As she fed you, plate in hand,
Mother pointed to the faraway moon!
Now, the time has come
For mother to taste the moon!
The people who waited
With yearning looks in their eyes
They can now sail to the skies...
How was it?
For sorrow has met its demise!
They can now sail to the skies
"Pechi says he will fly.
But I know he won't rest
until he makes everyone fly with him!"
My darling!
My dear boy!
You've won! God bless you!
Bless you, my boy!
-Your father is back!
-[mobile ringing]
Hello. A call for you, Maara.
Watch what you say.
Hello?
Congratulations, Mr. Nedumaaran!
Can we meet?
I have a business proposal for you.
I was expecting your call, Mr. Goswami.
Yeah, good!
I'll have my secretary
fix an appointment. Okay?
Who are you to give me an appointment?
What?
It doesn't matter whether I'm around now,
farmers have flown
and will continue to fly.
You don't own the sky, you scum.
Mr. Maaran!
Now fuck off.
Take me on now if you will
Lay a finger on me, I go for the kill
I'm a beast on the charge!
Mowing down all as I march on!
Take me on now if you will.
Lay a finger on me, I go for the kill.
He's the reason behind middle-class people
being able to afford plane tickets.
Here.
Why are you messing with me, you hag?
What do you want?
Want to fly for a buck, huh?
[all cheering]
Forget the plane, buddy!
The cakes which they provided!
So damn delicious!
I'll fly over and over
just for these cakes!
Whose idea was it?
The sky awaits us all...
It's such a pleasure to meet up with you!
-How is everything, sir?
-How dare you sabotage the plane I was in.
Let's see how your planes are gonna fly!
Sir, please let me explain!
Those who call this a fool's errand
Just admitted to being fools!
They show up first in line to kiss up
When victory is met!
Those who call this a fool's errand
Just admitted to being fools!
First time flyer?
No! I've flown these things in circles!
It's okay.
Yeah... first time.
As we get closer, the dream grows nearer!
Let's sow big dreams in our heads!
Any obstacle in our path,
Let's tear it to shreds!
-What do you do?
-I run a grooming establishment.
-What's that?
-I cut hair in my village.
-I see...
-Own business!
-And you?
-I run a business, too!
Don't you recognize him?
He has a huge clothing store in Madurai!
He gave 31 lakhs
to our fund for Maaran! A big man!
There's no difference between us anymore!
He's broken down all that
and made us fly together!
Maara...
Did that girl fly the plane?
Stand by and do nothing?
It will never respect you!
To hell with business class!
Tear it apart!
If they pay for tickets,
they can sit anywhere they want!
...won't it change one day
to a celebration sans failures?
Why are you hurrying to pay me back?
You'll need more money as you're growing.
Feel free to ask anytime!
We should make a film about you
and run it here!
You succeed and they
shamelessly suck up to you!
This owl-eyed fool thinks
he's director Bharthiraja or what?
It isn't too far off!
As we get closer, the dream grows nearer!